<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:googleplay="http://www.google.com/schemas/play-podcasts/1.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[The Missing KEI]]></title><description><![CDATA[The Missing KEI]]></description><link>https://keiboarder.substack.com</link><image><url>https://substackcdn.com/image/fetch/w_256,c_limit,f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fsubstack-post-media.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2Ffa36dd31-27ca-4676-b411-747651165770_48x48.png</url><title>The Missing KEI</title><link>https://keiboarder.substack.com</link></image><generator>Substack</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 03:55:11 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://keiboarder.substack.com/feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><copyright><![CDATA[Keiboarder, LLC]]></copyright><language><![CDATA[en]]></language><webMaster><![CDATA[keiboarder@substack.com]]></webMaster><itunes:owner><itunes:email><![CDATA[keiboarder@substack.com]]></itunes:email><itunes:name><![CDATA[Keiboarder]]></itunes:name></itunes:owner><itunes:author><![CDATA[Keiboarder]]></itunes:author><googleplay:owner><![CDATA[keiboarder@substack.com]]></googleplay:owner><googleplay:email><![CDATA[keiboarder@substack.com]]></googleplay:email><googleplay:author><![CDATA[Keiboarder]]></googleplay:author><itunes:block><![CDATA[Yes]]></itunes:block><item><title><![CDATA[Tech Essentials: Key Terms Everyone Should Know]]></title><description><![CDATA[No more nodding along in meetings while feeling lost!]]></description><link>https://keiboarder.substack.com/p/tech-startup-essentials-key-terms</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://keiboarder.substack.com/p/tech-startup-essentials-key-terms</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Keiboarder]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 05:14:20 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://substackcdn.com/image/fetch/w_256,c_limit,f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fsubstack-post-media.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2Ffa36dd31-27ca-4676-b411-747651165770_48x48.png" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 style="line-height:normal">Welcome to Your Tech Journey!</h2><p>Starting any tech project can feel like learning a whole new language. Don't worry - we're here to help you understand all those confusing words people throw around in meetings!</p><p>This week, we're breaking down 5 super important terms every non-technical person needs to know. Let's jump in!</p><h2 style="line-height:normal">&#127939;&#8205;&#9792;&#65039; Agile</h2><p><strong>What it is:</strong> A way to build software bit by bit instead of all at once.</p><p><strong>Why it matters:</strong> <a href="https://keiboarder.com/blog/a-to-z-tech-terms-for-first-time-founders">Agile</a> helps your team deliver working pieces of your product every few weeks. This means you can see real progress and make changes as you go!</p><p><strong>Real talk:</strong> Without Agile, many teams get stuck building for months with nothing to show. That's a recipe for wasted money and sad investors!</p><p><strong>Try this:</strong> Start with simple 2-week "sprints" where your team promises to finish specific tasks. Then check what got done and plan the next 2 weeks.</p><h2 style="line-height:normal">&#128187; Codebase</h2><p><strong>What it is:</strong> All the code that makes your product work.</p><p><strong>Why it matters:</strong> Your <a href="https://keiboarder.com/blog/a-to-z-tech-terms-for-first-time-founders">codebase</a> is like the foundation of your house. If it's messy or poorly built, everything on top becomes shaky!</p><p><strong>Real talk:</strong> Many founders don't realize they need to keep track of where their code is stored and who has access. This can cause huge problems later!</p><p><strong>Try this:</strong> Make sure your code is stored in a proper system like GitHub, not just on your developer's laptop (yes, this happens!).</p><h2 style="line-height:normal">&#127912; Prototype</h2><p><strong>What it is:</strong> A simple version of your product that shows how it will work.</p><p><strong>Why it matters:</strong> A good <a href="https://keiboarder.com/blog/a-to-z-tech-terms-for-first-time-founders">prototype</a> helps you test your idea without spending a ton of money building the real thing.</p><p><strong>Real talk:</strong> You can use tools like Figma to create clickable prototypes that look real but cost way less!</p><p><strong>Try this:</strong> Before hiring developers, create a prototype and show it to potential users. Their feedback might save you from building the wrong thing!</p><h2 style="line-height:normal">&#128640; MVP (Minimum Viable Product)</h2><p><strong>What it is:</strong> The simplest version of your product that solves the main problem.</p><p><strong>Why it matters:</strong> An <a href="https://keiboarder.com/blog/a-to-z-tech-terms-for-first-time-founders">MVP</a> gets you to market faster so you can start learning from real users.</p><p><strong>Real talk:</strong> The biggest mistake founders make is adding too many "cool features" to their MVP. This wastes time and money on things users might not even want!</p><p><strong>Try this:</strong> Write down the ONE problem your product solves. Then include only the features needed to fix that problem. Everything else can wait!</p><h2 style="line-height:normal">&#128506;&#65039; Roadmap</h2><p><strong>What it is:</strong> Your plan for what features you'll build and when.</p><p><strong>Why it matters:</strong> A clear <a href="https://keiboarder.com/blog/a-to-z-tech-terms-for-first-time-founders">roadmap</a> helps everyone understand what's coming next and why.</p><p><strong>Real talk:</strong> Sharing parts of your roadmap with users makes them feel included and excited about what's coming. Tools like <a href="https://keiboarder.com/blog/favorite-tools-for-first-time-tech-founders">Canny.io</a> can help you collect and organize feedback!</p><p><strong>Try this:</strong> Create a simple roadmap with three columns: Now (working on it), Next (coming soon), and Later (future ideas). This keeps your team focused on what matters most.</p><h2 style="line-height:normal">Want to Understand ALL the Tech Talk?</h2><p>Check out our complete A-Z guide of tech terms at <a href="https://keiboarder.com/blog/a-to-z-tech-terms-for-first-time-founders">keiboarder.com/blog/a-to-z-tech-terms-for-first-time-founders</a>!</p><h2 style="line-height:normal">Coming Next Week:</h2><p>Next week, we're sharing our top 5 paid tools that are worth every penny for anyone working with tech! Sometimes free just isn't enough - these powerful tools will save you tons of time and headaches, actually paying for themselves through better products and fewer mistakes.</p><p>At Keiboarder, we help startups to Fortune 500 companies avoid costly software development mistakes with expert fractional CTO leadership, a clear roadmap, and a proven process to build and scale market-ready products. <a href="https://keiboarder.com/contact">Get in touch with us</a>, and let's build awesome things together! &#128640;</p>]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>